《诉讼双雄》前情提要
一开始
When we started this thing,
我只是为了拍你的马屁
I was just doing it to kiss your ass
■
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
好让杰西卡原谅我
so Jessica would forgive me.
但你是个真正的人才
But you're the real deal.
在我看来  杰克·索罗夫
As far as I can tell, Jack Soloff
遵守了他的承诺
is holding up his end of the bargain.
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
不只这样
He's doing more than that.
他还发了一封邮件提名你作为初级合伙人
He just sent out an email nominating you for junior partner.
什么
What?
我不会发一篇通讯稿
I'm not sending out a press release
宣布哈佛毕业的迈克·罗斯升职了
announcing Mike Ross of Harvard just got promoted.
这是什么
What is this?
是我记错了  还是我们没讨论过这事
Am I mistaken, or did we not have this discussion?
别再打给我了
Don't call me again.
你得告诉路易你一直在跟埃斯特上床
You need to tell Louis you've been sleeping with Esther.
我们只睡了一次
We slept together one time.
有什么区别呢
What difference does that make?
你向他承诺了你不会这么做
You promised him you wouldn't do it at all.
我得告诉你一件事
I need to tell you something.
-你向我保证过的  -我告诉你
- You made a promise to me! - I'm telling you.
因为他在可怜的童年时期遭受了什么破事
Because he's so messed up from whatever goddamn thing
导致他现在这么人渣...
happened to him in his pathetic childhood, he can't--
闭嘴
Shut the hell up!
给杰里·迈耶斯打个电话
Get me Jerry Myers on the phone.
杰里·迈耶斯
Jerry Myers?
路易  发生什么事了
Louis, what happened?
我告诉你发生什么事了
I'll tell you what happened.
哈维揍了我一拳
Harvey took a goddamn swing at me.
-就是发生了这事儿  -天呐
- That's what happened. - Oh, my god.
是啊  "天呐"  我要告死他
Yeah, "Oh, my god," I'm gonna sue the shit out of him.
好了  路易  你受伤了
Okay, Louis, you're hurt.
你要做的第一件事是弄些冰块来
The first thing you need to do is get some ice
并且冷静下来
and calm down.
你没听见我说的话吗
Did you not just hear me?
他打了我然后把我摔在了一张咖啡桌上
He hit me and then he threw me into a coffee table,
所以我要告死他
so I am going to sue the shit out of him!
我不认为起诉哈维是解决之道
I don't think suing Harvey is the answer.
你当然不觉得了  因为你想要保护他
Of course you don't, because you want to protect him
就像当时你骗我
like you did when you lied to me
没把他对埃斯特做的事告诉我一样
about what he did to Esther.
听我说  我告诉哈维要他自己和你坦白
Listen to me: I told Harvey to tell you himself.
而我骗了你
And I lied to you
是因为我知道你要不是听他亲口说
because I knew something like this would happen
就会发生像现在这样的事
if you didn't hear it directly from him.
确实是发生了  唐娜
Well, it did happen, Donna.
现在马上给我打电话给杰里·迈耶斯
Now get me Jerry Myers on the phone.
你想要我这么做  我会做的
You want me to do that, I will.
但你总是说我们是一家人
But you've always said we're a family,
而家丑不可外扬
and families keep things like this in the family.
我不确定说"恭喜"是否妥当
I'm not sure if congratulations are in order,
但既然我们没有别的选择
but since we have no other choice,
我还是选择说"恭喜"吧
I'm going to choose congratulations.
-你看见那个备忘了  -看见了
- You saw the memo? - I did.
你要当合伙人了
You're making partner.
不  瑞秋  我不会当的
No, Rachel, I'm not.
什么意思
What do you mean?
杰西卡要我拒绝
Jessica told me to turn it down.
她说这会给我吸引过多的注意力
Said it would draw too much attention to me.
简直疯了
That's crazy.
假如你拒绝了  就会吸引更多的注意力
If you turn it down, you'll draw even more attention to yourself.
我就是这么和她说的
That's exactly what I told her.
那她怎么说
And what did she say?
她说假如我足够聪明  不上法学院
She said that if I'm smart enough to be a lawyer
也能成为律师  那我也就足够聪明
without going to law school, I should be smart enough
能想出个借口拒绝掉
to come up with an excuse to turn it down.
放屁
Oh, that's bullshit.
你以为我不想当合伙人吗
You think I don't want this?
我想的
I do.
当我们一直都知道我永远也当不了合伙人
But we've always known I was never gonna make partner.
好吧  那你准备怎么办
Okay. What are you gonna do?
我要做和我惯常做法相反的事
I am gonna do the exact opposite of what I usually do.
我不会去证明杰西卡错了
Instead of trying to prove Jessica wrong,
而是会想出一个合理的借口
I'm gonna come up with a legitimate excuse
解释我为何不能接受
for why I can't accept it.
杰西卡
Jessica,
我要知道你过来
if I knew you were coming over,
会准备好龙舌兰和鸡蛋的
I would have made us some tequila and eggs.
而我会用它们糊你一脸
And I would have thrown them in your face.
那可不怎么友好啊
Well, that doesn't seem very nice.
我准备它们是想讨你欢心的
I cooked them just like you like them.
你觉得这很有趣吗
You think this is funny?
你攻击了一名冠名合伙人
You assaulted a name partner.
而我在和你打哈哈就是因为我不想听这个
And I'm making jokes because I don't want to hear it,
因为他是罪有应得
because he got what he deserved.
我不在乎他有多大罪过
I don't care if he deserved a court martial.
那种行为不能存在于我的律所当中
That kind of behavior cannot exist in my firm!
你是说我们的律所吧
You mean our firm?
假如是我们的律所
If it's our firm,
那么也是路易的律所
then it's Louis's firm, too.
好了  我明白你的意思了
Okay, you made your point.
我不会再犯了
I won't do it again.
你以为我大老远跑到你这里来
You think I came all the way down here
只为了说教你吗
just to give you a speech?
你从明天开始休两周的假
You're taking two weeks starting tomorrow.
我去度假
Me going on vacation
可不能阻止路易对付我
isn't gonna stop Louis from coming at me.
会阻止的  因为假如在之后的两周内
Yes, it is, because if you set foot
你踏进办公室附近的任何区域
anywhere near the office in the next two weeks,
我保证他会申请停你职停三个月的
I guarantee he will call for a three-month suspension.
那就不要让他这么做啊
Then don't let him.
哈维  我们律所是有规章制度的
Harvey, there are bylaws in place,
而阻止他的唯一办法就是你休假
and the only way to stop him is you being on vacation.
唯一的问题是
The only problem with that is,
人人都知道我从不休假
everyone knows I don't take vacations.
那为何我手上有你两个月前
Then why am I holding your request
写的休假申请
that you filled out two months ago?
路易不会买账的
Louis is never going to buy that.
我才不管他是否买账呢
I don't give a shit whether he buys it or not.
但在你开始你的小旅途之前
But before you go on your little trip,
你得夹着尾巴去找他
you're going to go to him with your tail between your legs
然后告诉他你之前百分百错了
and tell him that you were 100% wrong.
杰西卡  你好呀
Jessica, hey.
有什么能为您效劳
What can I do for you?
你可以告诉我
Well, you can tell me
为何提名迈克·罗斯做初级合伙人
why you nominated Mike Ross for junior partner
但却没想着要知会我一声
and didn't think to run it by me.
这是公开提名
It's an open nomination.
我不觉得自己必须和你说
I didn't think I had to.
我没说你必须
I didn't say you had to.
我只是问你为什么没说
I asked you why you didn't.
我不明白
I don't understand.
是你逼他和我合作的
You were the one who forced him to work with me.
我是说和他合作  而不是背着我提名他
I said work with him, not nominate him behind my back
只为了对付哈维
just to stick it to Harvey.
杰西卡  我们还要讨论几次这件事
Jessica, how many times are we gonna have this conversation?
你给了我一个求和的机会
You gave me a chance to make peace
而我抓住了这个机会
and I took it.
而且到现在我也没听到一个好理由
And I still haven't heard one good reason
解释为何不能给迈克升职
why Mike shouldn't be promoted.
我没说他不够格当合伙人
Oh, I didn't say he didn't deserve to be partner.
那我撤回我的备忘
Then how about I retract my memo
让哈维来提名他如何
and let Harvey nominate him instead?
除非有原因导致这样你也不愿意
Unless there's some reason why you don't want that either.
因为与其跟我谈这件事
Because instead of talking to me about this,
你更该跟我谈谈昨晚路易和哈维之间
you should be talking to me about what happened last night
发生的事
between louis and harvey.
翻译： 香茗小焙 辰星晓Reginamoon 鱼小姐  木浅薰
翻译：某羽 杨一勾 小饭 某茶 菲力
时间轴：风吹来的那片云     校对：油炸电风扇   某羽
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第八集
-进展如何  -不太好
- How's it going? - Not great.
你还没找到拒绝提名的方法
You haven't found a way to turn down the nomination?
我想出了15种拒绝的方法
Oh, I've found 15 ways to turn it down.
但都不够好
But none of them are good enough.
肯定有一个很完美
Come on, one of them has to be good enough.
瑞秋  拒绝的理由不是重点
Rachel, it's not about the excuse,
重点是我得能直视那些人的眼睛
it's about me being able to look these people in the eye
说服他们相信这个理由
and convince them that it's true,
可我做不到
and I can't do that.
好吧
Okay.
那你要怎么办
What are you gonna do?
不知道
I don't know.
我知道
I do.
你要处理这个
You're doing this.
作为经营合伙人
As managing partner,
我正式委派给你第一个案子
I am officially giving you your first case.
-天哪  -怎么了
- Oh my god. - What?
经营合伙人给初级合伙人
It's tradition that the managing partner
分配升职后第一个案子是律所的传统
to give all new junior partners their first case.
-这是那个案子吗  -没错
- Is that what this is? - Yes, it is.
恭喜你  迈克
Congratulations, Mike.
虽然此事不在我计划之中
It may not be what I wanted,
但我是真心认为你值得这个职位
but I really did mean it when I said you deserve it.
谢谢你  杰西卡
Thank you, Jessica.
我不敢相信居然就这么成了
I can't believe that just really happened.
你是律所迄今为止最年轻的初级合伙人
You are the youngest junior partner the firm has ever had.
迈克  我真为你骄傲
Mike, I'm so proud of you.
那接下来就只剩一件事要做了
Well, that means there's only one thing left to do.
瑞秋·伊丽莎白·赞恩
Rachel Elizabeth Zane,
你愿意做我成为合伙人后
will you be the associate
第一个案子的助理律师吗
on my first case as partner?
愿意  我愿意
Yes. Yes.
问我多少次我都愿意
A thousand times, yes.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你是说你为打了路易感到很抱歉吗
Are you saying you're sorry you hit Louis?
我说的是我很遗憾没打得再狠点
I'm saying I'm sorry I didn't punch him harder.
如果是这样  我认为休假两周
In that case, I think taking two weeks off
的确是最合理的做法
is the best thing right now.
因为你现在
Because your emotions
完全被情绪所左右了
are completely ruling you.
想让路易闭嘴可不是被情绪左右的表现
Wanting to shut Louis up isn't being ruled by emotions.
这叫人有人性
It's being human.
但还有其他方法可以做到这一点
And there are other ways you could have tried to do that.
-比如  -比如转身离开
- Such as? - Walking out the door, for one.
我可不会离开我自己的办公室
I'm not walking out of my own office.
为什么
Why not?
因为别人拿枪指着你的时候
Because when someone points a gun at you,
你不能转身逃跑
you don't turn around and run away.
你要抢下枪  威胁回去
You take it out of their hand and you point it right back.
有时候让对手放弃攻击的最好方法
Well, sometimes the best way to get someone
是你自己先放下盔甲
to stop firing bullets at you is to take off your armor.
你说的那叫什么攻击
What the hell kind of bullets are you talking about?
情绪上的
Emotional ones.
哈维  路易朝你发火是因为他痛苦
Harvey, Louis lashed out at you because he was feeling pain,
而他用愤怒来掩盖他的痛苦
and instead of showing you his hurt, he covered it with anger.
那是他的问题  不是我的
Well, that's his problem, not mine.
要我说  其实你俩的问题一模一样
Actually, I'd say you two have exactly the same problem.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你与他的做法一模一样
You did the same thing to him that he did to you.
你用愤怒掩盖自己的痛苦
Instead of showing your hurt, you lashed out in anger.
唯一的区别是你动了手
The only difference is, is that you did it with fists.
他只动了嘴
He did it with words.
你是让我告诉他  我在看心理医生
Are you saying that I should tell him I'm in therapy
再跟他谈谈我的问题
and talk about my issues with him
然后我俩就能手拉手唱圣歌了吗
so we can sit around singing kumbayah?
我是劝你  如果你觉得路易应该为
I'm saying that if you think Louis should be sorry
朝你发火感到抱歉  那你至少
for lashing out at you, the least you can do
应该为朝他动手向他道歉
is apologize for lashing back at him.
路易  你怎么样了
Louis. How are you?
少客套了  我没兴趣
Cut the small talk. I'm not interested.
那么你找我有什么事
In that case, what can I do for you?
你可以拿哈维是怎么被罚的做开头
You can start by telling me how Harvey's being punished.
-那是我和哈维之间的事  -真有意思
- That's between me and Harvey. - That's funny.
他打我的时候  还是我和他之间的事呢
When he was attacking me, it was between me and Harvey,
我想知道你要怎么处理
And I want to know what you're gonna do about it.
我说过了  那跟你无关
And I just said, it's none of your business.
那么你作为经营合伙人  我要通知你
Then as managing partner, you should know
我要起诉你的大宝贝
that I'm suing your favorite son
罪名是骚扰和殴打
for assault and battery.
路易  你还没正式提交文件
Louis, you haven't filed that yet,
所以你不如告诉我你到底想怎样
so why don't you tell me what the hell you really want?
哈维得停职
I want Harvey suspended.
三个月  无薪  不能接触客户
Three months, no pay, no access to clients.
那不叫惩罚哈维
That's not punishing Harvey.
那是惩罚我们大家
That's punishing all of us.
你不愿意我自己来
Well, then I'll do it myself,
这是章程赋予我的权利
which I have the right to do under the bylaws.
路易  我本希望你现在已经冷静了
Louis, I was hoping you'd calm down.
如果两周后你还想这么做
But if you still feel this way in two weeks,
我也无力阻止
there's nothing I can do about it.
什么两周  你说什么呢
Two weeks? What the hell are you talking about?
你还没听说吧  哈维度假去了
You haven't heard. Harvey's on vacation.
一派胡言
Bullshit Harvey's on vacation.
哈维从来不放假
Harvey doesn't take vacations.
路易  你想让他走  他已经走了
Louis, you wanted him gone, and he's gone.
他亲笔签名的申请在这呢
And I have his signed requisition right here.
我不光希望他走
I don't just want him gone.
我还想当着全律所的面羞辱他
I want him humiliated in front of the whole firm,
而不是躺在土耳其什么地方的海滩上
not lying on a beach in Turks and Caicos
嘲笑你捏造的假申请
laughing at some fraudulent requisition you concocted.
那可是个恶劣的指控  路易
Oh, that's a nasty allegation, Louis.
你有证据吗
Do you have proof?
杰西卡  你这么做和我把哈维的工资单
You know what, Jessica, this is no different than me
放在复印机里没有差别
putting Harvey's salary in the copy machine.
差别大了去了  路易
Oh, it's entirely different, Louis.
你那么做是为分裂我们
You did that to rip us apart,
而我是为了把我们团结在一起
and I'm doing this to keep us together.
所以你还是赶紧离开我的办公室
So why don't you walk the hell out my office
仔细想想你到底想怎么玩下去
and think very carefully about how you want to play this?
他们来之前  我们先过一遍手里的信息
All right, before they get here, let's get our facts straight.
放松  我们的客户被谷歌提议收购
Easy, our client's being acquired by Google,
但奥泰拉软件公司有优先购买权
but Optela Software has a buy option.
他们宣称自己有优先购买权
Claims to have a buy option.
而且六个月前就过期了
It actually expired six months ago.
那为什么还跟他们见面
Then why are we having this meeting?
因为他们的律师不知道我们知道过期的事
Because their lawyers don't know we know that,
而且他们希望从中抽点好处
and they're hoping to get something to go away.
我要教你的太多了
Man, I have so much to teach you.
怎么  你现在成我上司了
What, are you my boss now?
这跟之前有区别吗
Oh, how is that different than before?
我现在可以甩手离开  留你孤军奋战
I could leave you high and dry right now.
你知道吧
You know that, right?
见鬼
Shit.
迈克  我只是在开玩笑
Mike, it was a joke.
瑞秋  我需要你独自解决这次会议
Rachel, I need you to handle this meeting by yourself.
-什么  怎么了  -他们的律师刚刚到了
- What? What's wrong? - Their lawyer just got here.
她吗
Her?
以前我当邮递员的时候
She used to work at a nonprofit
她在一家非盈利组织工作  明白吗
when I was a bike messenger, all right?
我们约过几次会
We went out a few times.
迈克  拜托  我能处理这种...
Mike, please. I can handle that--
不不不  她知道我没上过法学院
No, no, no, she knows I didn't go to law school.
-什么  -如果她看见我
- What? - If she sees me,
她就会知道我不是个律师  明白吗
she's gonna know I'm not a lawyer, all right?
我需要你来解决这次会议
I need you to handle this meeting.
-你能行吧  -不不  迈克  先别走
- Can you do that? - No, no, no--Mike, please.
你得给我点时间让我消化一下你说的话
You have to give me a second to process what you're saying.
瑞秋  我现在没有时间了
Rachel, I don't have a second.
-我需要你做这件事  -好吧
- I need you to do this. - Okay.
好吧
Okay.
克莱尔·鲍登
Claire Bowden.
瑞秋·赞恩
Rachel Zane.
我们开始吧
Shall we get to it?
好  当然
Yes, definitely.
我们...我们开始吧
Let's...let's get to it.
首先  我需要通知你
First of all, I need to inform you
我们准备申请临时禁制令
that we are prepared to move forward with a TRO,
当然  除非你的委托人改变心意
unless, of course, your client has had a change of heart.
你们可以这样做
You can do that.
我只是觉得不会有哪位法官会批准你的临时禁制令
I just don't see any judge granting you a TRO
考虑到你们的优先购买权已经过期了
given that your option has expired.
实际上  没有过期
Actually, it hasn't.
这是一份我们两边委托人之间的
This is a record of a phone call
通话记录
between our client and yours.
在这次通话中
A phone call during which
我的委托人同意帮助你的委托人修补漏洞
our client agreed to fix bugs in your client's software
以换取将我们的优先购买权
in exchange for a five-year extension
延期五年
of our purchase option.
我有点不明白  你们...
I'm confused. Do...
你们真的想要收购我们委托人的公司吗
Do you actually want to buy our client's company?
是的  如果确实要进行交易
Yes, if there's a deal happening,
我们希望能够实际参与其中
we want to be included in a meaningful way.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我没有权力让你们参与任何交易
I'm not authorized to include you in any deal.
那就现在打电话给你的委托人
Then pick up the phone and call your client.
我明白了
I understand.
你也没有权力那样做  因为某个合伙人
You're not authorized to do that either because a partner
最后一刻把这个案子甩到你面前
dropped this in your lap in the 11th hour.
你绝对想象不出我现在的处境
You have no idea.
其实我明白  我也遇到过这种事
No, I've been there before.
但我确实需要给我的委托人一个答复
But I need something to take to my client.
所以请你尽快给我回音  好吗
So, get back to me as soon as you can?
好的  当然
Yes, absolutely.
太好了
Great.
顺便问一句
By the way,
办这个案子的合伙人多大年纪了
how old is the partner on this case?
问这个干什么
Why would you ask that?
因为我注意到他的名字是迈克·罗斯
Because I noticed that his name was Michael Ross,
我和一个迈克·罗斯约会过一次
and I went out with a Mike Ross once.
我只是想知道是不是同一个人
I was just wondering if it was the same guy.
因为如果是同一个人
Because if it is,
那他真是完全扭转了人生
he really turned his life around.
我...我也不确定他具体多少岁了
I...I'm sure how old he is.
这是我们第一次合作
This is the first time we've had a case together.
所以...大概45吧
So I--maybe he's about 45?
-那肯定不是他了  -抱歉
- Oh, definitely not him. - Sorry.
你不用说抱歉
Oh, you don't have to be sorry.
我只是好奇而已
I was just wondering.
-谢谢  -应该的  当然
- Thank you. - Yes, of course.
怎么样
How'd it go?
-不怎么样  -发生了什么事
- Not well. - What happened?
他们的优先购买权并没有过期
What happened was their buy option didn't expire
因为结果发现我们做过一个延期交易
because it turns out we made a deal to extend it.
好吧  那确实让事情复杂化了
Okay, yeah, that complicates things.
他们会要求我们付更多的钱来解除优先购买权
They're gonna want to squeeze us for more money to go away,
但也没什么大不了的
but it's not that big a deal.
没什么大不了的吗
It's not that big a deal?
你从那间会议室里落荒而逃
You practically ran from that conference room
躲到这里  留我一个人去面对那个
to come and hide in here and left me to deal with a woman
知道你秘密的女人
who knows your secret,
然后你还告诉我没什么大不了的
and you're gonna tell me that it's not that big a deal.
我是说得向奥泰拉公司付钱没什么大不了的
I meant having to pay off Optela is not that big a deal.
你都没有告诉我她是怎么知道你的秘密的
You didn't even tell me how she knows your secret.
她不知道我的秘密  好吗
She doesn't know my secret, all right?
我告诉她我在上法学院
I told her I went to law school,
然后她发现我其实没有
and she found out I didn't.
如果她现在见到我
If she sees me now,
就会去仔细调查我  然后她就会发现
she's gonna look into me and then she'll know it.
那你当初为什么
And why did you tell her
要告诉她你在上法学院
that you went to law school in the first place?
-瑞秋  这不重要  -这对我很重要
- Rachel, it's not important. - It's important to me.
因为我想在她面前博得好印象
Because I wanted to impress her,
而一个小邮递员做不到那一点
and being a bike messenger wasn't gonna do it.
所以你为了和她约会而骗她吗
So you lied to her to get a date?
是的  我是那样做的
Yes, I did.
现在你不是唯一一个对她撒谎的人了
Well, you're not the only person who's lied to her now.
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
意思就是  她向我问起了你
What it means is, she asked me about you,
然后我不得不撒谎
and I had to lie to keep her from thinking
让她以为你不是她以前认识的那个迈克·罗斯
that you're the same Mike Ross that she knew before.
瑞秋  对不起  我...
Rachel, I'm sorry. I...
-你要去哪  -去处理你的案子
- Where are you going? - To work on your case.
至于那个上述的案子
As for the aforementioned case,
把证词练习记录发给委托人
send our client his practice depo,
而且要标出所有他不应该在宣誓后说的
and underline all self-incriminating things
自证其罪的话
that he's not supposed to say under oath.
那个白痴
Idiot.
接下来是...
Moving on to...
唐娜  快叫保安
Donna, call security.
我在自己的办公室里感觉不安全
I do not feel safe in my own office.
唐娜已经回家了
Donna went home.
我来单独和你谈谈
I'm here to speak to you alone.
为什么  这样你再打我
Why? So you can have no witnesses
就没有目击证人了吗
the next time you attack me?
不  这样我可以私下向你道歉
No, so I could apologize to you in private.
不行  不行  不行
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
你不能光道个歉就逃过这一次
You're not gonna apologize your way out of this one.
我不是来逃过什么的
I'm not here to get out of anything.
我是来说对不起的
I'm here to say I'm sorry.
我一时失控  我不该打你的
I flew off the handle, and I shouldn't have punched you.
你不只是打了我  你攻击了我
You didn't just punch me. You attacked me.
-路易  -扯淡
- Louis-- - Bullshit.
这都是扯淡
This is all bullshit.
你这个人根本就有问题
There is something wrong with you,
不管你对我说什么...
and there is nothing that you could ever possibly say to me--
我一直在看心理医生
I have been seeing a psychiatrist.
什么  不  不可能
What? No, you haven't.
这又是什么花招
This is some kind of trick.
我一直在看心理医生治疗恐慌症
I've been seeing someone to get help for panic attacks.
你恐慌症发作过吗
You've been having panic attacks?
-是的  -在哪里
- Yes. - Where?
我不想说得太详细
Look, I don't want to get into it.
在哪
Where?
办公室里
In the office.
什么时候
When?
随时可能发作
They happen when they happen.
路易  我跟你说的是实话
Louis, I am telling you the truth.
天呐  这种情况持续多久了
My god. How long have they--
几个月前开始的
they started a few months ago.
几个...  唐娜离开时吗
A few--when Donna left?
没错  从唐娜离开时开始
Yes, when Donna left.
但不完全是因为唐娜
But it isn't really about Donna.
那只是个诱因  至少他们是这么告诉我的
That was a trigger--at least that's what they're telling me.
原因要深得多
It goes deeper.
跟我的家庭
My family,
我的感情问题  都有关
my relationships.
我现在正努力处理一堆糟心事
Let's just say I'm trying to work through some shit.
所以我说的那些话刺激了你的神经
So when I said those things, it struck a nerve.
不仅如此  路易
Oh, it did more than that, Louis.
那些话伤害了我
It hurt.
你也伤害了我  哈维
You hurt me too, Harvey.
我知道  我很抱歉
I know, and I'm sorry.
虽然这不是个借口
And it's not an excuse,
但我想让你知道我为什么打了你
but I wanted you to know why I did what I did
这一切的根源何在
and where it was coming from.
你不是真的要去特克斯和凯科斯群岛  对吧
You're not really going to Turks and Caicos, are you?
不知道  但我下午接受了治疗
I don't know, but I had therapy this afternoon,
还花了一整天时间
and I spent the rest of the day
考虑怎么做才最好
trying to figure out the best way to do this.
路易  埃斯特的事我很抱歉
Louis, I'm sorry for Esther.
很抱歉对你说谎
I'm sorry for lying to you.
也很抱歉打了你
And I'm sorry that I attacked you.
我接受你的道歉  哈维
I accept your apology, Harvey.
谢谢你  路易
Thank you, Louis.
那你不会再让我停职了
So you're not gonna try and suspend me?
让你停职
Suspend you?
杰西卡很确定你会想让我停职
Jessica was sure you'd want to suspend me.
杰西卡不知道你会说刚刚那些话
Jessica didn't know that you were gonna say what you said.
事实上  我知道杰西卡
As a matter of fact, I know jessica
让你休假只是为了缓解情况
only sent you on vacation to defuse the situation,
所以我觉得你明天应该回来上班
so I think you should come back tomorrow.
-你确定吗  -是的
- You sure? - Yes.
他们将宣布迈克晋升合伙人
They're announcing Mike's partnership,
我不希望你错过这个时刻
and I wouldn't want you to miss that.
-谢谢  路易  -这是我最起码能做的
- I appreciate that, Louis. - It's the least I can do.
我能跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you for a second?
如果是谈你成为高级合伙人的事
If it's about you becoming senior partner,
我觉得有点太早了
I think it's a little premature.
我们可能有麻烦了
We may have a problem.
可能  还是已经
May or do?
元桌面案子的对方代表律师
The lawyer on the other side of the Metadesk case
知道我没上过法学院
knows that I didn't go to law school.
什么
What?
会议前我看到她走进公司
I saw her come into the office
所以就让瑞秋接管了
before the meeting, so I had Rachel take over,
她还不知道我是她认识的迈克·罗斯
and she's doesn't know I'm the same Mike Ross she knew,
她也不会知道  但是
and she's not going to, but--
该死的第一个案子
Goddamn first case.
杰西卡  事情会解决的  我保证
Jessica, it's gonna be handled. I promise.
瑞秋会和我一起工作
Now, Rachel and I will work together,
但她将一直代替我出面
but she'll be out front the whole time.
除了让她应付着
Well, I guess we have no choice
我们也没有别的选择
but to let her ride it out.
但如果有人发现你第一个案子
But it's gonna look pretty damn sketchy
就交给助理  会显得有问题
if someone finds out you've handed off your first case.
所以才有了下一个问题
Which brings me to my next point.
杰克·索罗夫在过问这个案子
Jack Soloff has been asking about it.
那你最好保证不被他发现
Then you better make damn sure
你让瑞秋负责这个案子
you keep him from finding out you put Rachel in charge.
因为我们最不希望杰克·索罗夫
Because the last thing we need is for Jack Soloff
开始调查你的过去
to start sniffing around your past.
没错  我知道
Yeah, I know.
如果这些你都知道
Well, if you know all these things,
还来这做什么
then why exactly are you here?
因为你信任我  让我做了合伙人
Because you trusted me with being partner
我想让你知情
and I'm trying to repay that trust
借此来回报你的信任
by keeping you in the loop.
我很感激  迈克
I appreciate that, Mike.
但你回报我的最好方式
But the best way for you to repay me
就是首先确保那个律师
is by making sure that other lawyer
不会发现你那该死的秘密
doesn't find out your goddamn secret in the first place.
-有给我带吗  -没有
- Get one of those for me? - No, I didn't.
你不能像平时一样抢我的面包圈
And you can't take mine like you usually do.
放松点小老虎  我不是来抢你的面包圈的
Easy, tiger, I'm not here to take your bagel.
我是来给你这个
I'm here to give you this.
你怎么能这么快搞定
How'd you get that done so fast?
我有个熟人
I know a guy.
你有个熟人在做定制雕刻
You know a guy in custom engraving?
我到处都有熟人
I know a guy in everything.
谢谢  哈维  你不用这么做的
Oh, thanks, Harvey, but you didn't have to do that.
你又不是每天都有晋升合伙人这么好的事
Come on, it's not every day you make partner,
我认为没有人比你更应该得到这个职位了
and I've never known anyone who deserves it as much as you.
除了你之外
Except for you.
这一点我们心知肚明  不必说出口
Well, that goes without saying.
那你为什么要说
So why'd you say it?
因为不得不说
Because it had to be said.
说真的  迈克
Seriously, Mike,
这是你应得的  我很高兴你做到了
you deserve this. I'm glad you got it.
我只是希望我是那个晋升你的人
I just wish I could have been the one that made it happen.
我很高兴在和路易发生那样的事之后
I'm just glad you made it in for the meeting
你还能出席会议
after everything that happened between you and Louis.
不管你相信与否
Believe it or not, it was Louis who actually
是路易邀请我回来工作的
invited me to come back to work.
你怎么说服他的
How'd you manage to get him to do that?
即使我告诉你  你也不会相信
Well, you wouldn't believe me if I told you.
但即使他没有邀请我回来
But even if he hadn't invited me back,
就算来支军队也无法阻止我参加你晋升合伙人的表决
an army couldn't have kept me away from your partnership vote.
拜托  哈维  这只是个形式
Come on, Harvey, it's just a formality.
他们已经给了我头衔
They've already given me the title.
这也许只是个形式
It may be just a formality,
但如果我不投票支持  会议不可能举行
but that meeting's not happening without my vote on the record.
下一个待表决的项目正是
The next item up for bid on the price is right
迈克·罗斯被提名为
is Mike Ross's nomination
初级合伙人
for junior partner.
我知道这只是个形式
Now, I know it's just a formality,
但有人提出异议吗
but what do you say we make it unanimous?
所有支持这个决议的人请举手
All those in favor?
那么我很高兴地宣布迈克·罗斯
Then I'm pleased to announce Mike Ross
成为公司最新的初级合伙人
as this firm's newest junior partner.
如果没有其他事...
So, if no one else has anything--
我有事要说
I have something.
如果你们都在疑惑
If you're all wondering why
为什么我的头骨严重受伤
I have extensive damage to my skull,
那是因为两天前
it's because two nights ago,
哈维·斯佩克特恶意袭击了我
I was viciously attacked by Harvey Specter.
鱿鱼我希望不要去律所外部寻求司法途径
And since I would rather not go outside the firm
依照公司章程第28b条
to take legal action, pursuant to section 28-b of the bylaws,
我提议让哈维·斯佩克特立刻免薪停职
I am placing Harvey Specter on immediate unpaid suspension.
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
我不知道这事该怎么解决
Okay, I don't really know how this works.
是不是有人该叫保安了
Should someone call security?
路易  我觉得没人需要叫保安
Louis, I don't think anyone needs to call--
-我有权利  -事实上路易  你没有
- It's my right. - Actually, Louis, it's not.
28章b条确实是停职章程  但是
Section 28-b does require suspension, however,
只有在合伙人
it's enforceable only
都投票认为你所言不虚的情况下
after a vote by the partners to determine
才能生效
if what you're claiming even happened.
-我所言不虚  -我没说不是
- Oh, it happened. - I'm not saying it didn't.
我只是在引述你自己写的章程原文
I'm just quoting the bylaws you wrote.
所以  我提议周五专门投票一次
Therefore, I'd like to schedule a vote for friday,
也好给大家一个认清事实的时间
once we've all had a chance to review the matter.
好吧  这不是我想要的
Okay, this is not what I want--
章程是你自己写的  路易
They're your bylaws, Louis...
就定在周五吧
So friday it is.
会议结束
Meeting adjourned.
瑞秋
Rachel.
-很高兴见到你  -我也是
- Good to see you. - You too.
我得承认  我很惊讶
I have to admit, I'm surprised
你们这么快就给了我回复
you're getting back to us so soon.
当我们意识到了你们的真实目的后
Well, once we realized what you really wanted,
就觉得无需等待了
we figured why wait?
那我们的真实目的是什么
And what is it that we really want?
说实话吧
Let's be honest.
你的委托人根本
Your client has no real interest
没有兴趣涉足执行软件行业
in the fulfillment software business.
不  其实并非如此
No, that's not actually true--
但你们确实延长了追诉期
But you do have an extension of your purchase option,
虽然庭上站不站的住脚还不一定
which may or may not hold up in court.
所以我们愿意出这个价钱来平息事端
So we're willing to pay you this to go away.
我觉得上次见面你可能对我的表达有误解
I think maybe you misunderstood me in our last meeting.
我不是什么法人杀手
I'm not some corporate killer
想以此要挟你们多给钱
who's looking to hold you hostage for a payoff.
我的委托人是真心想入伙
My client actually wants to be included in this deal.
克莱尔  这已经是很合理的出价了
Claire, this is an incredibly fair offer.
我并不认为这出价合理
I don't think this is a fair offer at all.
那就谈谈否则之后吧
Well, then let's talk about what would be,
因为你的委托人不可能入伙
because your client's not staying involved in this deal.
这是你上司的立场还是你的
Is this your boss's stance or yours?
是我们的委托人立场  也就是律所的立场
It's our client's, and my firm's,
而且我不喜欢你质疑
And I don't appreciate you questioning
我在交易里的地位
my role in this deal.
瑞秋  我昨天放你一马
Look, Rachel, I cut you some slack yesterday
是因为你是个不知所措的菜鸟
because you're a newbie who's in over her head,
但既然你无权
but since you clearly don't have the power
让我们入伙
to include us in this deal,
我认为我应该直接联系负责本案的合伙人
I think maybe I should call the partner on this case.
我告诉你  你可以这么做
You know what? You should.
因为他会告诉你
But he's just gonna say this:
如果你申请临时限制令  我们就会
if you pursue a TRO, we'll sue you
以侵权干扰生意业务关系罪起诉你
for tortious interference.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你本来就知道交易正在进行
You knew this sale was in process,
但你故意等到结算
and you waited till closing
才提出议案
to broach the topic.
-这就叫侵权干扰生意业务关系  -好
- That is tortious interference. - Okay.
看来我们也没什么好谈的了
Well, I think we're done here.
拿着钱离开吧
Just take the money and walk away,
否则我们会在法庭上纠缠好多年
or we will tie this up in court for years.
选择权在你们  可说回来  我知道什么呢
It's up to you. But then again, what do I know?
我只是个菜鸟
I'm just a newbie.
你这个满嘴谎话的贱人
You lying piece of shit.
我说谎是因为我不是你以为的那个蠢货
I lied because I'm not the fool you think I am.
你说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
我在说你的真心道歉
I'm talking about your apology from the heart.
你真的让我为你那些废话感动了
You actually had me falling for that bullshit
感动到你问我是不是要让你停职
until you asked me if I was gonna suspend you.
那一刻我就知道  全是控制
And then I knew it was just all a goddamn manipulation.
你觉得我敞开心扉  告诉你我有恐慌症
You think me opening up about having panic attacks
是为了控制你
is manipulation?
我都不觉得你真有恐慌症
I don't even think you really had panic attacks,
就更别说去看心理医生了
let alone are going to therapy.
我有  而我对你说出实情
Well, I am, and I opened up to you about it,
之后你却看着我的眼睛
and then you looked me in the eye,
利用迈克的晋升会议引我回来
and you used Mike's partnership to lure me back.
是的
Yes.
我是那么做了
I did.
因为我想让你知道
Because I wanted you to know how it feels when someone
一个人当你面承诺了一件事又做出完全相反的行为时
says one thing to your face and then turns right around
那种感受  就像你对我做的事一样
And does the exact opposite, like you did to me.
那这是对我睡你妹妹的报复吗
So this is payback for me sleeping with your sister?
-当然是  -你这个贱人
- Sure as shit is. - You son of a bitch.
我应该现在就把你拎出去
I should take you outside right now--
干嘛  再打我一次吗
And do what? Hit me again?
这次可就不只是停职了  哈维
Because this time it won't just be a suspension, Harvey.
-你会被开除  -够了
- You'll be gone. - That's enough.
没人要打谁
No one's hitting anybody.
哈维  在投票前  你不许跟他单独相处
Harvey, you're not to be alone with this man before that vote.
挺清楚了吗
Is that clear?
这事没完
This isn't over.
杰西卡  谢谢
Thank you, Jessica.
律所应该是个安全的环境
A law firm should be a safe environment,
而我开始觉得很担心...
and I started to feel like I was fearful--
闭嘴  路易
Shut the hell up, Louis.
你刚才的行为太卑鄙了
What you did in there was despicable.
极其卑劣  仇怨
It was underhanded and vindictive
对整个律所都有伤害
and harmful to the entire firm.
我猜你不会投票惩罚哈维了
I take it you won't be voting to discipline Harvey.
我就不会去投票
I won't be voting at all.
如果你以为自己能把我扯进这烂事
And if you think you're gonna drag me into your bullshit,
那你就得准备好其他麻烦了
then you have another thing coming.
你弃权随你
Oh, you can abstain all you want,
但所有人都会知道你的立场
but everyone's gonna know exactly where you stand.
他们早就知道我的立场
They already know where I stand.
绝不是支持你
And it's not with you.
你用起诉把她拍回去了
You slapped her with a lawsuit?
她联系你了
Did she call you?
不  她联系了谷歌  而谷歌给我电话
No, she called Google, and then they called me
说他们要退出交易
to tell me they're pulling out of the deal.
-什么  -是的  他们不希望
- What? - Yeah, they don't want
冒此时被扯进官司里的风险
to run the risk this thing gets tied up in litigation,
所以要退出
so they're out.
-迈克  我可以解释  -不  你不用解释
- Mike, I can explain. - No, you don't have to explain.
我们上次对话时你已经解释过了
You explained the last time we talked.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你对克莱尔有意见
You've got a problem with Claire,
你在用这案子发泄
And you're taking it out on this case.
我对克莱尔没意见
I don't have a problem with Claire.
我有意见的是你对她撒谎
I have a problem with you lying to her
说你上法学院
about going to law school.
但我威胁她要起诉的原因
But the reason I threatened that suit
是因为她不满意控制不住我
is because she didn't like not getting her way with me,
而想给你打电话
and she was going to call you instead.
你是避免了那种事发生
Well, you stopped that from happening,
但在此过程中  毁掉了整桩交易
and in the process, you blew up the entire deal.
你听我说了吗  她要给你打电话
Did you hear me? She was going to call you.
所以我很抱歉谷歌退出
So I'm sorry that Google pulled out,
可我没什么机会
but I didn't really have the chance
考虑所有选择
to think of every option--
所有选择  只有一个选择
Every option? There's only one.
就是你们再商量一个价钱
You negotiate another price.
你以为我没试吗
You think I didn't try that?
她唯一会接受的
The only thing she would have accepted
就是插足这个交易  没了
is being cut in on the deal, period.
我只知道如果当时我在场
All I know is that if I'd been there,
肯定会想出办法搞定
I would have figured out a way to get it done.
你忘了吗  你不可能在场
Well, you know what? You couldn't have been there.
而且我也不喜欢你现在告诉我
And I don't appreciate you telling me
我没有你优秀  因为一开始
that I'm not as good as you when the only reason
我参加那个会议就是为了
I was in that meeting in the first place
给你打掩护
was to cover for you.
瑞秋  抱歉  我没想针对你
Rachel, I'm sorry, I didn't mean to make it personal.
你指责我因为嫉妒搞砸了
Well, it sure sounded personal when you accused me
当然就是针对我
of screwing up because I was jealous.
我刚说过抱歉
Look, I just said that I'm sorry.
我只是以哈维在这种情况下
I'm only coming down on you the same way
对待我的方式对待你罢了
Harvey would come down on me in the same situation.
行  可你不是哈维  我也不是你
Right, but you're not Harvey, and I'm not you.
如果是哈维用刚才
And if Harvey was talking to you
你对我的口气跟你说话
the way that you're talking to me,
你现在就会在这跟我抱怨他多混蛋了
you would be in here right now telling me what a dick he is.
-把那个给我行吗  -什么
- Can I have that, please?  - What?
我还没把你昨天的录音记完...
I haven't done your transcriptions since yesterday, so...
那不着急  回家吧
Oh, it can wait. Go home.
怎么了
What?
你今天太过分了  路易
You went too far today, Louis.
这么说你不是来做事的
So, you're not really here to do work.
你来只是为了帮哈维说话
You're here to once again take Harvey's side.
我没有要帮哈维
I'm not taking Harvey's side,
但你在会上的所作所为是不对的
but what you did in that meeting was wrong.
你告诉我家事不外扬  我照做了
You told me to keep it in the family, and that's what I did.
我的意思是让杰西卡处理  你也清楚
I meant let Jessica handle it, and you know it.
但杰西卡并没有处理
But Jessica didn't handle it.
她想让哈维去加勒比度假
She tried to send Harvey to the Caribbean.
那你唯一的选择就是
Oh, so the only thing that you could do was blindside him
在迈克升合伙人的会议上使阴招吗
in the same meeting where Mike is made junior partner?
他袭击了我
He assaulted me.
我明白  路易
I understand that, Louis.
但我不明白
But what I don't understand
为什么明明是你怒气冲冲的去找他
is why you're the one who went in there angry,
最后却是他打了你
and he's the one who ended up attacking you.
-唐娜  -你对他说了什么
- Donna-- - What did you say to him?
我犯不着跟你解释
I don't have to explain myself to you.
对  你犯不着  你爱怎么做怎么做
No, you don't, and you're free to do whatever you want.
我看到你被他打过的脸
But when I saw your face after he hit you,
我是真心为你难过
I felt horrible for you.
可既然你不告诉我你说了什么
But since you won't tell me what you said to him,
我开始觉得  可能不值得为你难过
I'm starting to wonder if I should.
这是什么
What's this?
我知道因为这个案子
I know you had to reschedule the cake tasting
得改期蛋糕试吃  所以
because of the case, so
我想我可以把蛋糕带回来给你尝
I thought I'd bring the cake tasting to you.
你不必这么做
You didn't have to do that.
我想  因为我想确定
I wanted to, because I wanted to make sure
你明白不管工作上发生什么
that you know that no matter what's going on at work,
你在我生命中都是最重要的
you're the most important thing in my life.
我知道你是在努力不让我被抓
I know you were just trying to keep me from getting caught.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
我也是
I'm sorry, too.
为什么
What for?
尽管我很不想承认
Because as much as I hate to admit it,
我确实对克莱尔心存嫉妒
I do have a problem with Claire.
瑞秋
Rachel--
迈克  我当时就坐在她对面
Mike, I was sitting across the table from her,
我完全可以理解你当初为何喜欢她
and I could see all the reasons why you were interested in her.
我不禁去想如果她从未发现你撒谎
And I--I had to wonder what would have happened
又或者她在一年后
if she'd never found out that you lied,
更了解你时才发现
or if she found out a year later
事情又会怎样
after she'd gotten to know you better.
或许你们俩还在一起
Maybe the two of you would still be together.
-不会的  -你怎么知道
- We wouldn't be. - How do you know?
或许我想了一想才告诉你真相
Because it might have taken me a while to tell you the truth,
但从我第一眼见到你的时候
but from the first second I looked at you,
就想把我的一切摊开在你面前
I wanted to tell you everything about me.
当我终于告诉你真相时
And when I finally did tell you the truth,
你没说你再也不想见到我
you didn't tell me that you never wanted to see me again.
你接受了我
You accepted me.
实际上我扇了你一巴掌
Actually, I slapped you.
-然后你吻了我  -对
- And then you kissed me. - Yeah.
还继续和我在一起
And stayed with me.
无论如何都爱我
And loved me anyway.
-杰克  -有什么能效劳  哈维
- Jack. - What can I do for you, Harvey?
我想感谢你今天为我出头
I wanted to thank you for standing up for me today.
我告诉杰西卡我准备好跟团队合作了
I told Jessica I'm ready to be a team player.
或许现在你们俩会相信我了
Maybe now the two of you will believe me.
这我还不太确定
Well, I don't know if I'm willing to go that far,
但我感激你今天所做的
but I appreciate what you did.
能让我说几句吗
Can I speak freely?
说吧
Go ahead.
这是你应得的
You've earned it.
我告诉迈克
I told Mike the reason
我一开始就针对你是因为
that I went after you in the first place
对你来说一切都来得容易
was that everything comes easy to you,
但这么想的可不是我一个人
but I'm not the only one that feels that way.
你想说什么
What's your point?
我或许能暂时阻止路易
I may have stopped Louis
让你停职
from suspending you for the moment,
但投票的结果可能对你不利
but that vote's not gonna go well for you.
你是说我能做些什么改变结果
You're saying I can do something to change the outcome.
我是说你可以做些什么改变
I'm saying you could do something to change the way
其他合伙人对你的看法
the partners feel about you.
你希望我自愿接受停职吗
You want me to take this suspension voluntarily?
如果这事发生在一个月前
If this were a month ago,
我会希望你把名字从墙上拿掉
I'd want you to take your name off the wall.
但你的确需要做出谦逊的姿态
But you need to do something to humble yourself.
具体怎么做  是你自己的决定
What exactly that is, is up to you.
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
接待处告诉了我你的办公室
The receptionist told me where to find you.
她不该这么做
Well, she shouldn't have,
不如你自行离开吧
so why don't you find your way out?
克莱尔  我是来道歉的
Claire, I'm here to apologize.
你说我没经验
Look, you got under my skin
让我很不舒服
when you called me inexperienced
因为我确实没做多久
because the truth is I haven't been doing this very long.
所以我就采取反击
So I shot back,
于是就越界想...
and I went overboard to try and--
证明你比我强
Show me that you were better than me.
没错  结果我们两败俱伤
Yes, and I ended up blowing the deal for both of us,
对不起
And I'm sorry.
俗话说吃一堑长一智
Well, they say you learn from your mistakes.
没错
That's the thing.
我已经吸取教训了
I have already learned,
我认为我找到了双赢的办法
and I think that I have a way to get both of us a win.
格格丹  你们的大客户
Gigadyne. They're a major client at your firm.
不如你让他们来收购元桌面
What if you were to bring them the acquisition of Metadesk?
他们为什么要买
Why would they want this?
因为他们需要执行软件来
Because they need fulfillment software
提高他们在欧洲的销售量
to increase their sales in Europe,
而我们就是最佳选择
and we're a perfect fit.
你调查了我的客户
You researched my client?
我说过了  吃一堑  长一智
Like I said, I learn from my mistakes.
-你好啊  -少来这套
- Hey. - Oh, don't "Hey" Me.
你是无事不登三宝殿
You're up to something.
干嘛这么说
Why would you say that?
我为你工作了12年
I worked for you for 12 years.
你觉得我还分不出你有没有事吗
You think I can't tell when you're up to something?
-唐娜  -哈维
- Donna-- - Harvey,
既然你是来这里找的我
If you're coming to me in here,
那就说明你不想让路易知道
that means you don't want Louis to know.
可我已经不再为你工作了  我现在是他的人
And I don't work for you anymore--I work for him.
我知道  我也知道我将要问的事情
I know that, and I know what I'm about to ask
可能会置你于两难之地
might put you in between me and Louis.
但我希望你能帮我  看看我能做些什么
But I want you to help me figure out something I can do
阻止合伙人停我的职
that'll move the partners not to suspend me.
那就告诉我
Then tell me this.
那天路易跟你说了什么  居然能让你动手打他
What did Louis say to you that made you hit him?
为什么要问这个
Why are you asking me that?
因为你让我和你一伙
Because you're asking me to pick your side,
那我就要知道你是不是值得
and I need to know if you deserve it.
唐娜
Donna,
要是到现在了你都还不了解我
if you don't know me well enough to know
觉得我不值得你帮的话
that I deserve your help by now,
那我再说什么都是徒劳
nothing I tell you is gonna matter.
而无论我是否值得
But whether I deserve it or not,
我可以向你保证  路易会用阴招
I guarantee you Louis is going to have some dirty trick
为这次的投票做准备
up his sleeve for that vote.
路易  我有话跟你说
Louis, I need to talk to you for a second.
如果你是来劝我别玩阴的
Well, if you're here to tell me not to play dirty,
那就别白费口舌了  因为唐娜已经劝过了
you're wasting your breath because Donna already did it.
我不是来劝你的
I'm not here to do that,
因为你已经在玩阴的了
because you already played dirty.
我是来劝你给哈维停职投反对票的
I'm here to get you to vote against suspending Harvey.
什么叫我已经在玩阴的了
How the hell have I already played dirty?
你明知我的合伙人资格对哈维来说有特殊意义
You knew my partnership would mean something to Harvey,
可你非但没有让此事避免涉入你们的纠纷
and instead of holding it outside of your feud,
反而利用它把他骗回了律所
you used it to trick him back into the firm.
迈克  那是因为这是得到正义的唯一方式
Because, Mike, it was the only way to get justice.
好
Okay.
如果你是这么想的话  那换句
If you think that, then let me put this in terms
你能懂的话说  就是
that you might understand.
哈维是琼恩·雪诺  而我是他的班扬叔叔
Harvey is Jon Snow, I'm his Uncle Benjen,
你利用我把他引出来
and you used me to lure him out
这样大家就可以一人一刀把他捅死了
so that everybody could stab him to death.
你竟敢把哈维比做琼恩·雪诺
How dare you defile Game of Thrones
这绝对是对《权力的游戏》的玷污
by comparing Harvey to Jon Snow.
你明知道  这不是重点
That's not the point, and you know it.
重点是  你背叛了哈维
The point is, you betrayed Harvey,
就像那个小孩背叛琼恩·雪诺一样
the same way that kid betrayed Jon Snow.
话虽如此  可那是为了所有的守夜人
Well, in that case, it was for the good of the Watch.
是啊  我觉得那小孩肯定也是这么想的
Yeah, I'm sure that's what that kid thought, too.
但我向你保证  他之后的一生都会在
But I guarantee you, he's going to regret stabbing his friend
害过朋友的悔恨和痛苦中度过
for the rest of his miserable life.
捷运快递服务
丹尼尔·哈德曼办公室
Daniel Hardman's office.
立刻让他听电话
I need to speak to him right now.
请问是哪位来电
Who may I say is calling?
你知道是谁  史黛西
You know who it is, Stacy.
快让他接电话
Now get him on the goddamn phone.
他现在不在  但他有给你留言
He's not here, but he left word for you.
他寄了两个包裹
He sent two packages.
要么你按照一个继续
Either move forward on one of them,
要么他按照另一个继续
Or he'll move forward on the other.
-祝贺你  -贺什么
- Congratulations. - On what?
祝贺你作为初级合伙人赢了第一个案子啊
On winning your first case as junior partner.
我赢了作为初级合伙人的第一个案子吗
I won my first case as junior partner?
你有了一个超棒的主意
Mm-hmm, turns out you had a brilliant idea.
真的吗  我想出了什么好主意
Oh, really? And what was my brilliant idea?
等我跟其他合伙人聊天时
You know, for when I'm sitting around
就可以好好吹一下了
shooting the shit with the other partners.
你让我回去找克莱尔
You sent me back to Claire
提议说让她自己的客户买下元桌面
to propose that she have one of her own clients buy Metadesk
让奥泰拉也加入进来
and let Optela stay on board.
瑞秋  这想法真是太棒了
Rachel, that's amazing.
我不敢相信她竟然真的同意了
I can't believe she went for it.
她同意了  格格丹也同意了
She went for it, and Gigadyne went for it.
你刚刚是说了格格丹吗
Did you just say Gigadyne?
是啊  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
瑞秋  格格丹刚公布了他们会
Rachel, Gigadyne just announced they're getting into
接手国防部外包业务
the Defense contracting business.
-什么  什么时候的事  -是的
- What? When? - Yeah.
昨天  他们已经签了第一份合同了
Yesterday--they already have their first contract.
就是说我刚刚让这项交易涉及到的每个人
Which means I just triggered a background check
都要接受背景调查
on every single person involved in this deal.
迈克  真对不起
Mike, I am so sorry.
不会  你也不知道会这样
No, you couldn't have known.
而且我们也没有时间说对不起
And we don't have time for "I'm sorrys" anyway.
在一切还来得及的时候
We have to find a way to take care of this
我们得赶紧想办法补救
before it's too late.
我们该怎么做
How are we gonna do that?
我们要大变活人
We're gonna hide in plain sight.
我不懂
I don't understand.
我们要把我的名字从所有的文件上删除
We're gonna take my name off all of the paperwork,
然后祈祷没人发现
and we're gonna hope to god nobody notices.
你在这里干嘛
What are you doing in here?
赶上我的工作进度啊
Catching up on my work.
-有问题吗  -没有
- Is that a problem? - No.
就是我跟你说过了
It's just that I told you
不用你再抄录这些了
that I didn't need you to do any transcribing.
你说话时的语气让我想起了
And the way you said it got me thinking
你有多喜欢把你的计划都录在里面
about how you like making your plans on this thing.
然后我就听到了这个
And then I came across this.
唐娜
Donna--
你觉得我对你敞开心扉
You think me opening up
告诉你我有恐慌症是在控制你吗
about having panic attacks is manipulation?
我都不觉得你真有恐慌症
I don't even think you really had panic attacks,
更别说去治疗了
let alone are going to therapy.
我有
Well, I am.
而我对你说出实情
And I opened up to you about it,
之后你却着我的眼睛
and then you looked me in the eye,
利用迈克的晋升会议引我回来
and you used Mike's partnership to lure me back.
是的
Yes.
是我做的
I did.
因为我想让你明白这种感受
Because I wanted you to know how it feels
当一个人当面承诺你一件事
when someone says one thing to your face
转身就做了
and then turns right around
完全相反的事  就像你对我做的
and does the exact opposite, like you did--
他把这些事情告诉了你
He revealed those things to you,
可是你却录下来  为了放给其他的合伙人听
and you recorded him so you could play it for the partners?
我不是想录他说的那些东西
I wasn't trying to record him saying those things.
我只是想拿到他打我的证据
I just wanted proof that he hit me.
胡说
Bullshit!
你根本不在乎你拿到的是什么
You didn't care what you got.
你只是想打倒他
You just wanted to get him.
你还真说对了
You're damn right I did.
他打了我
He hit me.
他抢走埃斯特
He got Esther.
他永远随心所欲
He gets away with everything.
也许是的
Maybe he does.
如果你想让他被停职
And if you want to try to get him suspended,
那是你的权利
that's your right.
但你利用他的弱点公开羞辱他
But if you use his weaknesses to publicly humiliate him,
我就不再为你工作了
I'm done working for you.
瑞秋
Rachel,
你在这里做什么
what are you doing here?
我们已经把所有合同发回去了
We already sent back all of the contracts.
我知道  我只是过来一下
I know, I just came by
你忘记最后一页的签名了
because you missed a signature on the last page.
不  我没忘
No, I didn't miss it.
-我只是想暂缓签署  -为什么
- I was holding off on signing it. - Why?
因为我在想你为什么做了
Because I was wondering why you made changes
七处不同的增补  却不告知我
to seven different addendums without redlining them for me.
那只是签署页几个合伙人名单
They're just signatory pages of a few lists of partners,
我不觉得有必要做告知
so I didn't think that that warranted a redline.
是你不觉得  还是你的合伙人不觉得
You didn't or your partner didn't?
我们都不觉得  他在国防部有个客户
Neither of us did. He has a big client in defense,
而且虽然我们不代理格格丹
and so even though we don't rep Gigadyne,
他也担心他们认为有利益冲突
he was worried they might see it as a conflict.
他担心的不是利益冲突
The reason he's worried is not because of a conflict.
是交易会引发背景审查
It's because this transaction triggers a background check.
-也就是说  -我告诉你原因了
- Which means-- - I told you the reason.
他在代理另一位客户  而且...
He's repping another client and--
他在骗你  瑞秋
He's lying to you, Rachel.
你会觉得这很难相信
You're gonna find this impossible to believe,
但迈克·罗斯是个骗子  他知道我知道这点
but Mike Ross is a fraud, and he knows that I know.
所以他最后一刻派你来了
That's why he sent you in at the last minute
可这明明从一开始就是他的交易
when this was his deal from day one.
你疯了吗  他是
Are you crazy? He's a partner
皮尔斯-斯派克特-利特律所的合伙人
at Pearson, Specter, Litt,
而你说你的迈克·罗斯不是45岁
and you said your Mike Ross wasn't 45.
所以我认识的迈克...
So the Mike that I know--
天呐  你知道
Oh, my god, you know.
我什么都不知道  除了我们需要...
I don't know anything, except that we just need--
你要不告诉我发生了什么
I'm calling the D.A.'s office right now if you don't tell me
我就给检察官办公室打电话
what the hell's going on.
我们订婚了
We're engaged.
所以确实是他
So it is him.
克莱尔  求你  你不能告发他
Claire, please, you can't turn him in.
这跟我不能怎么做无关
This isn't about what I can't do.
你发现了这事  怎么还能跟那样的人在一起
How could you be with a man like that after you found out?
因为我已经爱上他了
Because I already loved him.
抱歉了  瑞秋
Well, I'm sorry, Rachel.
我没法选另一条路
I just can't turn the other way.
你知道你纵容了什么吗
Don't you understand what this is condoning?
我明白
Yes, I understand what it's condoning,
但你设身处地为我想想
But you have to put yourself in my shoes.
想象你是在一年之后
Imagine you found out a year later,
已经了解了他的真实内心后才发现
after you already knew the kind of man he is inside.
克莱尔  我...
Look, Claire, I'm...
我跟你说
I'm telling you.
他确实不是律师
No, he's not a lawyer,
但他的确改变了他的生活
but he did turn his life around.
你是个聪明的姑娘  瑞秋
You're a smart woman, Rachel.
但你在犯一个天大的错误
But you are making a huge mistake.
求你了  求你了
Please, I am begging you.
完事了
It's done.
-她信了  -是的
- She bought it? - She did.
难以置信
I can't believe it.
你是觉得我搞不定吗
Did you think I couldn't handle it?
我猜我只是担心她总会想明白
I guess I was just worried that she'd figure it out anyway,
揭发我  然后...
expose me, and then--
没什么"然后"
There is no "And then."
因为根本没有发生
Because that didn't happen.
多亏了你
Because of you.
是多亏我们
Because of us.
你把戒指戴到办公室了
You're wearing your ring at the office.
是的
I am.
你为什么决定那么做了
What made you decide to do that?
我...只是发现了
I...I just realized
我有多爱你
how much I love you,
而且...
and...
也不想再藏着那份爱了
That's not something I ever want to hide.
瑞...
Ra--
杰西卡  我能跟你聊聊吗
Jessica, can I talk to you for a second?
什么事  路易  我正要下班回家
What is it, Louis? I'm heading home for the night.
我想取消投票
I want to call off the vote.
你说什么
Excuse me?
整件事都是错误
The whole thing was a mistake.
我想取消
I want to call it off.
路易  投票就在明早
Louis, the vote is tomorrow morning.
唯一让它不发生的方法
The only way it doesn't happen
就是你公开说明哈维没有打你
is if you publicly tell everyone that Harvey didn't hit you.
我不能那么做  我会失去信誉
I can't do that. I'll lose all credibility.
所以我才想让哈维休假两周
Which is exactly why I wanted Harvey to take two weeks.
就是要让你冷静下来
To let you calm down.
因为我知道你会改变主意
Because I knew you'd change your mind.
如果你不介意的话
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我还得准备投票
I have a vote to prepare for.
稍等  如果我改变投票立场呢
Wait, what if I flip my vote?
随你怎么改  路易
Flip whatever the hell you want, Louis.
但这事是你挑起的
But you started this ball rolling,
如今我们都得承担其结果
and now we all have to live with the consequences.
你不是在故意躲着我吗
I thought you were trying to avoid me.
之前是的
I was.
但我又想到你总会知道是我的
But then I figured out you knew it was me anyway.
怎么知道呢
How?
重要吗
Does it matter?
不重要
No, it doesn't.
那你来做什么
So why are you here?
我只想说谢谢你
I just wanted to say thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
我还想知道你为什么愿意放过我
I also wanted to know why you're letting it go.
因为瑞秋求我了
Because Rachel begged me to.
因为她说她爱你
And because she said that she loved you
而你改变了自己的生活
and that you turned your life around.
你相信她
And you believed her?
我相信她爱你
I believe that she loves you.
但你要真想知道事实
But if you really want to know the truth,
我不相信你能改变你的生活
no, I don't believe that you turned your life around,
而且绝对不相信你爱他
and I definitely don't believe that you love her.
什么  你怎么能这么说
What? How can you say that?
因为你说服她相信一切都会没事
Because you've convinced her that it's all gonna be okay,
你俩会从此幸福地生活在一起
that you two are just gonna get to live happily ever after,
我不想做那个
and I didn't want to be the one
毁掉一切的恶人
to make that all come crashing down.
但你知道吗  迈克
But you know what, Mike?
总有一天  这一切都会毁掉
One day, it is going to come crashing down.
如果你真爱她
And if you really do love her,
你会现在就停手
you'll put a stop to this right now.
你觉得我不该再做律师
So, you think I should stop being a lawyer?
我是说你要真爱她  就不会跟她结婚
I'm saying if you really love her, you won't marry her.